<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Advanced Topics on</title><link>https://rpm.staker.ltd/docs/advanced-topics/</link><description>Recent content in Advanced Topics on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rpm.staker.ltd/docs/advanced-topics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Signing Key Rotation</title><link>https://rpm.staker.ltd/docs/advanced-topics/signing-key-rotation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rpm.staker.ltd/docs/advanced-topics/signing-key-rotation/</guid><description>Rotation policy Our keys have a cryptoperiod of 3 years which is the maximum recommended by NIST SP 800-57. This is significantly shorter than most signing keys used by distribution/software maintainers, hence our use of bundled keyring via the staker-repo package to support key rotation.
In practical terms a key isn&amp;rsquo;t used to sign releases for the full 3 years period as the key rotation needs transition periods. Therefore, the key lifecycle is as follows:</description></item><item><title>Infrastructure</title><link>https://rpm.staker.ltd/docs/advanced-topics/infrastructure/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rpm.staker.ltd/docs/advanced-topics/infrastructure/</guid><description>Design The RPM repositories themselves are nothing fancy. All they require is a basic HTTP server to be delivered.
Our repositories are published as Cloudflare pages and delivered via Cloudflare. This allows us to provide them at no cost for the community besides our use cases.
Signing key delivery Our signing keys are delivered initially from Keybase i.e for repository bootstrap procedure. This is by design. If the signing key and the repository are delivered by the same server (which is a common example for quite a few software vendors), then the trust can not be established as the chain of custody may be broken.</description></item></channel></rss>